A Guide to the League of Women Voters of the Richmond Area Archives 1920-1997
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
League of Women Voters of the Richmond Area Archives 1920-1997
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 18
3.5 linear feet
League of Women Voters of the Richmond Area
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions
Acquisition Information
The collection was a gift to Special Collections and Archives from the League of Women Voters of thre Richmond Area
Biographical/Historical Information
The Virginia League of Women Voters (LWV) was organized on November 9, 1920 in the State Capitol building in Richmond. This date was chosen to coincide with the anniversary of the organization of the Equal Suffrage League of Virginia in 1909. The meeting was attended by women from all parts of the state.
The Richmond League organized a few weeks later, on November 30, 1920, in a meeting called by Adele Clark, one of several early LWV members who had been active in the women's suffrage movement in Virginia. The purpose of the organization, expressed in its original constitution, was "to stimulate education in citizenship and to suggest and support improved legislation."
The Richmond League has been active on a number of issues, including child welfare, women's rights at work, redistricting, and support for the Equal Rights Amendment. Throughout its existence it has encouraged citizen participation in elections. In the 1970's the name of the Richmond Area LWV was changed to the LWV of the Richmond Metropolitan Area, Virginia, Inc. -representing the areas of Richmond, Chesterfield County and Henrico County.
Scope and Content Information
The collection includes minutes, correspondence, annual as well as other reports, newsletters, newspaper clippings, notes, various publications and other materials. The date range of the collection, from the early 1920's until the present, spans the history of the organization. There seems to be some minutes missing from the years 1939 through 1945.
Much of the correspondence from the 1970s focuses on the passage of the Equal Rights Amendment and includes letters to and from Virginia's U.S. Congressional delegation. Numerous regional and state issues are also documented in the collection.
Arrangement
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically and chronologically within each donation. Some correspondence, news clippings and league publications are also found in the orginizations minutes. The 2003 donations of materials were added at the end of the collection under Series 2. Series 3 are the items related to the materials concerning the Project for Mental Health of Homeless. Series 4 are the materials donated thereafter. Donations made in 2006 by the LWV are Series 5.
Organization
The first deposit of materials from the LWV of the Richmond Area (7/12/83) included minutes, newsletters, correspondence and other materials, dates from 1920 until 1973. A second deposit (4/1/94) of similar materials dates from the late 1970s until 1992. The collection also includes four additional deposits of material: one from Geraldine Fineberg Archivist for the League of Women Voters of the Richmond Metro Area (95-Jun-24); a second from Muriel H. Smith (95-Jul-32), member of LWV of the Richmond Metro Area; a third deposit from Donna Reynolds (96-Oct-28); and a fourth deposit from an undetermined donor (97-Jun-12).
Contents List
- Donations made before 2003 1921-1994 (Box 1-10)
  - Action Alert Documents n.d. 1978, Feb. 1986, July 1987 (Box Box 1)
  - Annual Meeting Programs 1973-1979 (Box Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1955-1958 (Box Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1960-1970 (Box Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1970-1973 (Box Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1974-1979 (Box Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1980-1992 (Box Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1993-1995 (Box Box 1)
  - Annual Reports to State and National League 1955-1959 (Box Box 1)
  - Annual Reports to State and National League 1960-1965 (Box Box 1)
  - Annual Reports to State and National League 1966-1973 (Box Box 1)
  - Ballot Issues 1977, 1978 (Box Box 1)
  - Biographical Information on League Members n.d., 1976-1994 (Box Box 1)
  - Bliley, Thomas J.-Interview 1985 (Box Box 1)
  - Board Meeting 1977 (Box Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Agendas and Minutes 1982, 1986-1989, 1993-1994 (Box Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Annual Meetings 1965 (Box Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Annual Meetings 1966 (Box Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, Annual Meetings 1967 (Box Box 1)
  - Board Notes (Notebook) May 6, 1981-Jan. 6, 1983 (Box Box 1)
  - Board of Supervisors Election (Chesterfield and Henrico) 1983 (Box Box 1)
  - Book: Choosing the President-Published for the LWV Education Fund 1980 (Box Box 1)
  - Social Organization by Scott A. Greer 1955 (Box Box 1)
  - Virginia's Government 1975 (Box Box 1)
  - Budget Issue Seminar 1983 (Box Box 1)
  - Bylaws n.d.; Policy and Guidelines Handbook 1977, 1981, 1984 1988, 1990 (Box Box 1)
  - Bylaws and Guidelines for League Action n.d., 1981 (Box Box 1)
  - Candidate Questionaires-General Assembly-July 1965, Richmond City 1966 1965, 1966 (Box Box 1)
  - Candidates for Sheriff Questionnaires (Chesterfield and Henrico) 1983 (Box Box 1)
  - Capital Budget for Richmond 1983-1984 (Box Box 1)
  - Catalog of Federal and Additional Assistance to Richmond 1979 (Box Box 1)
  - Charter of Richmond, Virginia 1982 (Box Box 1)
  - Chesterfield County-Includes: Public Improvement Bonds, Service Directory, Plan 2000, Map, Precinctsk and an Article on Education; 1980-1982 (Box Box 1)
  - Chesterfield County Board of Supervisors Election 1979 (Box Box 1)
  - Child Care Information 1989-1990 (Box Box 1)
  - Children First in Virginia-program, undated. (Box Box 1)
  - City Budget and Finances 1985-1991 (Box Box 1)
  - City Council Election 1984 (Box Box 1)
  - City Planning Commission 1994 (Box Box 1)
  - Civil Rights Restoration Act 1985 (Box Box 1)
  - Coastal Preservation Program 1981 (Box Box 1)
  - Comprehensive Prevention Plan for Virginia (Publication) 1990-1992 (Box Box 1)
  - Congressional Debates 1992 (Box Box 1)
  - Congressional Election 1980 (Box Box 1)
  - Congressional Election 1982 (Box Box 1)
  - Congressional Interviews, Correspondence, and Notes 1983, 1985-1987 (Box Box 2)
  - Correspondence 1956 (Box Box 2)
  - Correspondence n.d., April-May 1978 (Box Box 1)
  - Correspondence June-August 1978 (Box Box 2)
  - Correspondence Sept.-Dec. 1978 (Box Box 2)
  - Correspondence 1979 (Box Box 2)
  - Correspondence-Letter to the Richmond Times Dispatch Regarding Abortion 1983 (Box Box 1)
  - Correspondence-Miscellaneous 1953-1956, 1960, 1962, 1976-1986 (Box Box 2)
  - Correspondence-Presentation to Virginia General Assembly, Dec. 6 1977 (Box Box 2)
  - Correspondence and Memorandums n.d., 1981-1993 (Box Box 2)
  - Correspondence with Newspapers 1976-1980, 1983-1985 (Box Box 2)
  - Debate Information 1988, 1992 (Box Box 2)
  - Debate/Meeting Locations 1988 (Box Box 2)
  - Debate-Presidential 1976 (Box Box 2)
  - Democratic and Republican Party Plans n.d. 1984, 1986-1988 (Box Box 2)
  - Demographic Profile of Richmond 1985 (Box Box 2)
  - Education in Virginia n.d. 1978-1980, 1989-1992 (Box Box 2)
  - Elderly n.d. 1980-1983 (Box Box 2)
  - Election 1984 (Box Box 2)
  - Election Districts, Laws, and Precincts for Chesterfield, Henrico and Richmond 1980-1983 (Box Box 2)
  - Election Guide 1984 (Box Box 2)
  - Enviromental Issues (Publications) n.d. (2 files) 1985-1992 (Box Box 2)
  - Equal Rights Amendment 1977-1978 (Box Box 2)
  - Executive Board Meeting Notes (Notebook) April-June 1981-1984 (Box Box 2)
  - 50th Anniversary-Fund 1969-1970 (Box Box 2)
  - 50th Anniversary Correspondence,invitations, interview with Adele Clark 1969-1972 (Box Box 2)
  - Finance Study n.d. 1984-1988 (Box Box 2)
  - Fiscal Policy Committee 1984-1985 (Box Box 2)
  - Forms and Information for Virginia Candidates 1984-1985 (Box Box 2)
  - Future Horizons: Virginia in the 20th Century Sept. and Dec. 1987 (Box Box 2)
  - General Assembly Election 1979 (Box Box 2)
  - General Assembly Election 1983 (Box Box 2)
  - General Registrars of Virginia (City and County) 1989 (Box Box 2)
  - Getting to Know Richmond n.d. 1980-1981 (Box Box 2)
  - Government Study-Chesterfield County January 1982 (Box Box 3)
  - Guide: Monitoring for Compliance with the Voting Rights Act 1987 (Box Box 3)
  - Guidelines for League Boards (Publication) 1980 (Box Box 3)
  - Guides to Chesterfield and Henrico n.d. 1969-1992 (Box Box 3)
  - Handbook for Virginia Mayors and Council Members n.d. (Box Box 3)
  - Handbook for the LWV of the United States 1989 (Box Box 2)
  - Henrico Board of Supervisors' Candidates 1982 (Box Box 3)
  - Henrico County Board of Supervisors Election 1979 (Box Box 3)
  - Henrico County Finances and Development 1985-1991 (Box Box 3)
  - Henrico County Telephone Directory 1984 (Box Box 3)
  - History of State Program Items-Election Law Reform, Mental Health, Fiscal Health, and Education 1970 (Box Box 3)
  - History of VLWV and the Richmond Area LWV 1970 (Box Box 3)
  - Housing n.d. 1978-1981 (Box Box 3)
  - Housing Equality and Quantity of Housing in Richmond n.d., 1968, 1971-1972 (Box Box 3)
  - Housing-Equality of Opportunity n.d. 1966-1968, 1971 (Box Box 3)
  - Housing Information on Richmond and Virginia n.d. 1970-1971 (Box Box 3)
  - Housing Investment Patterns in Richmond Report May 1981 (Box Box 3)
  - Housing Reports for Richmond 1981 (Box Box 3)
  - Impact on Issues (Publication) 1984-1988, 1990-1992 (Box Box 3)
  - Issues and Issue Papers 1980-1981 (Box Box 3)
  - Job Descriptions 1988 (Box Box 3)
  - Joint Commission on Health Care's Key Issues (Publication) 1993 (Box Box 3)
  - Know Your Local Government Study n.d., 1974, 1980-1981 (Box Box 3)
  - Know Your Local Government Study (Chesterfield, Henrico, Richmond) 1978-1983 (Box Box 3)
  - Know Your Local Government Study-Funding and Format n.d. 1978-1981 (Box Box 3)
  - Know Your Local Government Study-Guides and Assignments n.d., 1959-1969, 1977-1981 (Box Box 3)
  - Know Your Local Government Study-Housing n.d. 1970-1981 (Box Box 3)
  - Know Your Local Government Study-Housing Data 1970's (Box Box 3)
  - Know Your Local Government Study-Human Services 1979-1980 (Box Box 3)
  - Know Your Local Government Study-Intergovernmental Relationships 1980's (Box Box 3)
  - Know Your Local Government Study-Population Data 1970's, 1980's (Box Box 3)
  - Labels (Box Box 3)
  - Leadership Metro Richmond 1980-1981 (Box Box 3)
  - Leadership Metro Richmond-Final Program Ideas June 3 1981 (Box Box 3)
  - League Day-National Security Panel Discussion Sept. 1983 (Box Box 3)
  - Legislative Correspondence 1989 (Box Box 3)
  - Legislative Newsletter Jan.-March 1984-1985 (Box Box 3)
  - Legislative Packet 1989 (Box Box 3)
  - Local Government n.d. 1950's-1970's (Box Box 3)
  - LWV of Virginia-Miscellaneous (Box Box 3)
  - LWV Planning n.d. 1988-1992 (Box Box 3)
  - LWV Resource Material-Bylaws, Board Structures, n.d. 1981, 1984, 1987, 1992-1993 (Box Box 3)
  - LWV Richmond City Council Candidates Forum 1988 (Box Box 4)
  - LWV Richmond City Council Candidates Forum 1992 (Box Box 4)
  - LWVUS Calendars 1993-1994 (Box Box 4)
  - Maps-Chesterfield County Street Map, and Richmond City Voting Precincts Chesterfield-1987 and Richmond-1982 1987, 1982 (Box Box 4)
  - Maps-Henrico County Districts and Voting Precincts n.d. 1980-1991 (Box Box 4)
  - Meeting Notes (Notebook) 1983-1985 (Box Box 4)
  - Meeting Notes (Notebook) 1985-1986 (Box Box 4)
  - Meeting Notes (Notebook) Oct.-Jan 1986-1990 (Box Box 4)
  - Meeting Notes (Notebook) May 1990-1991 (Box Box 4)
  - Membership Directories 1951-1952, 1978, 1980-1981, 1981-1982, 1983-1984 (Box Box 4)
  - Membership Handbooks 1984-1993 (Box Box 4)
  - Membership Lists 1975-1980 (Box Box 4)
  - Membership Notes 1985 (Box Box 4)
  - Mental Health Association and LWV's Remember the Children Breakfast, and the Mental Health Study Consensus Report 1987-1989 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes (1 of 2) 1921 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes (2 of 2) 1921 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1922 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1923 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1925 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1926 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1927 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1928 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1929 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1930 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1931 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1932 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1933 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1934 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1935 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1936 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1937-1944 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1945-1949 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1950 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1953-1954 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1955-1956 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1957-1958 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1959-1962 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes 1963-1965 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes April-March 1967-1968 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes Apil-March 1968-1969 (Box Box 4)
  - Minutes April-March 1969-1970 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes April-March 1970-1971 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes April-December 1971-1972 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes 1969-1971 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes 1971-1972 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes 1972 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes 1973-1974 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes 1975-1978 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes Jan. 3, 1979-Dec. 1, 1982 1979-1982 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes Jan. 5, 1983-Dec. 4, 1985 1983-1985 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes April 23, 1985-April 2, 1986 1985-1986 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes Jan. 8-1986-Oct. 5, 1988 1986-1988 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes April-March 1986-1987 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes April-Dec. 1987 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes-Annual Meeting April 8, 1987 and Board Meetings Jan. 1988-Dec. 1989 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes March-June 1990-1991 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes (Annual Meetings) June 1991, 1992, and 1993 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes (Board Meetings) Aug.-June 1991-1993 (Box Box 5)
  - Minutes (from Executive Committee Meetings) Oct., Aug., and May 1991, 1992, 1993 (Box Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous n.d., circa 1950's 1974, 1977, 1989 (Box Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Information of LWV n.d. 1978-1994 (Box Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Papers n.d. 1947, 1976, 1981, 1985-1986, 1988-1990 (Box Box 5)
  - National Election Information 1980 (Box Box 5)
  - National Voter (Magazine Publication) Fall 1985-Oct. 1994 1985-1994 (Box Box 5)
  - National Voter Registration Sept. 9, 1988 (Box Box 5)
  - Newsclipping (Long Article on LWV) May 25, 1969 (Box Box 5)
  - Newsletters April-March 1963-1966 (Box Box 6)
  - Newsletters April-Nov. 1966-1967 (Box Box 6)
  - Newsletters Jan.-Nov. 1968-1969 (Box Box 6)
  - Newsletters 1970-1972 (Box Box 6)
  - Newsletters 1973-1974 (Box Box 6)
  - Newsletters 1975 (Box Box 6)
  - Newsletters 1976 (Box Box 6)
  - Newsletters 1977-1979 (Box Box 6)
  - Newsletters 1980-1983 (Box Box 6)
  - Newsletters 1983-1986 (Box Box 6)
  - Newsletters 1987-1989 (Box Box 6)
  - Newsletters 1990-1992 (Box Box 6)
  - Newsletters Jan.-May 1993-1995 (Box Box 6)
  - Newspaper Articles n.d. 1991-1993 (Box Box 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1953-1959 (Box Box 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1960-1965 (Box Box 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1966-1969 (Box Box 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1970-1974 (Box Box 7)
  - Nuclear Freeze 1985 (Box Box 7)
  - Older Virginians-Info on Housing and the Office on Aging n.d. (Box Box 7)
  - Ordinance-Concerning the Division of Richmond into 9 Districts for the election of City Council 1991 (Box Box 7)
  - Photographs n.d. (Box Box 7)
  - Planning Guides for Local and State Leagues 1980-1986 (Box Box 7)
  - Policy and Guidelines Handbooks 1977, 1984, 1992 (Box Box 7)
  - Popular Control of Government (Chesterfield, Henrico, and Richmond) n.d. 1980's (Box Box 7)
  - Position Papers 1980, 1989 (Box Box 7)
  - Post Board and Post Council Meeting Summaries June-June, and Jan.-June 1985-1987, 1991-1993 (Box Box 7)
  - Precinct Maps n.d. (Box Box 7)
  - President's Packets of the LWV 1986-1990, 1992 (Box Box 7)
  - Projects, Studies n.d., 1985-1993 (Box Box 7)
  - Public Safety 1979-1980 (Box Box 7)
  - Public Statements 1983-1987, 1993 (Box Box 7)
  - Public Welfare n.d., 1970, 1974-1975, and 1977-1980 (Box Box 7)
  - Publications-Solar Homes 1983 (Box Box 7)
  - Publications-Voter Guides, Miscellaneous Publications n.d. 1980's, 1990's (Box Box 7)
  - Recycling Guide 1988, 1990 (Box Box 7)
  - Reference Book and Directiory 1984-1985, 1985-1986, 1992-1993 (Box Box 7)
  - Report of the Governor's Commission on Virginia's Future 1984 (Box Box 7)
  - Report from the Hill (Publication) Feb.-Nov. 1986-1993 (Box Box 7)
  - Report on Racial Polarization in Richmond March 31, 1981 (Box Box 7)
  - Richmond n.d. 1960's-1984 (Box Box 7)
  - Richmond City Council Candidates Questionaire 1958 (Box Box 7)
  - Richmond City Council Election May 1978 (Box Box 7)
  - Richmond City Council Election May 1980 (Box Box 7)
  - Richmond City Council Election May 1982 (Box Box 7)
  - Richmond City Council Election May 1988 (Box Box 7)
  - Richmond City Schools (Education) n.d. (Box Box 8)
  - Richmond City Structure n.d. 1980 (Box Box 8)
  - Richmond Clean City, Committee Recycling Opportunities Publication 1988 (Box Box 8)
  - Richmond Council of Women's Organizations 1952, 1983-1987 (Box Box 8)
  - Richmond Department of Public Utilities Annual Report 1978-1979 (Box Box 8)
  - Richmond Health Services 1975, 1980 (Box Box 8)
  - Richmond Intergovernmental Relationships n.d. (Box Box 8)
  - Richmond Serial Public Improvement Bonds 1979-1980, 1982 (Box Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 1971-1981 (Box Box 8)
  - Secretary's Records Feb.-April 1978-1979 (Box Box 8)
  - Secretary's Records (Margaret Zajonc, secretary) April-May 1980-1981 (Box Box 8)
  - Secretary's Records (Sally Kenney, secretary) Jan.-April 1981-1982 (Box Box 8)
  - Secretary's Records March-April 1982-1983 (Box Box 8)
  - Secretary's Records (Janine Silberman, secretary) April-March 1983-1985 (Box Box 8)
  - Seminar with Chamber of Commerce on Understanding the General Assembly 1978 (Box Box 8)
  - 75th Gala (1 of 2) Feb. 14, 1995 (Box Box 8)
  - 75th Gala (2 of 2) Feb. 14, 1995 (Box Box 8)
  - Solar Homes Tour Materials 1983 (Box Box 8)
  - Special District Government in Va 1967 (Box Box 8)
  - State Convention Documents n.d. 1981, 1983, 1985-1987, 1992 (Box Box 8)
  - State Council Workbooks April 1978, 1986 (Box Box 8)
  - State Election Information 1980 (Box Box 8)
  - Statements of the LWV n.d. 1976-1977, 1983-1988, 1994 (Box Box 8)
  - Study on Henrico County Government and Education 1979-1981 (Box Box 8)
  - Superfund Materials n.d. 1981, 1984-1985 (Box Box 8)
  - University of Virginia Newsletter (Publication) 1963-1964, 1971, 1981-1982 (Box Box 8)
  - Virginia Election Laws 1980 (Box Box 9)
  - Virginia Election Laws 1992 (Box Box 9)
  - Virginia General Assembly Special Sessions 1981-1982 (Box Box 9)
  - Virginia Municipal Review April 1937 (Box Box 9)
  - Virginia Voter (Publication) 1979-1980 (Box Box 9)
  - Virginia Voter (Publication) Winter 1983-1986 (Box Box 9)
  - Virginia Voter (Publication) Spring-Winter 1986-1994 (Box Box 9)
  - Virginia's Water Supply Problems (Publication) 1982 (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Education Guidebook n.d. (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Education Guide for Kindergarten n.d. (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Education in Schools n.d., 1988, 1992 (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Registration 1976-1977, 1981, 1983, 1984-1985 (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Registration Drive 1990 (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Registration Drive 1992 (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Registration Street Directory for Richmond 1990 (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Service Information n.d. 1976-1978, 1980 (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Service Information 1986-1993 (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Service Materials 1983-1986 (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Service Materials 1984, 1988, 1991-1992 (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Service Materials 1990 (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Service Materials for Va 1990 (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Service Materials-Miscellaneous 1980-1995 (Box Box 9)
  - Voter Voter Service Programs 1991 (Box Box 9)
  - Women's Yellow Pages for Richmond 1993-1994 (Box Box 9)
  - Video-3 Congressional Debates 1992 (Box Box 10)
  - Video-Voting in Virginia (Box Box 10)
  - Video-Voting in Virginia (Box Box 10)
  - Video-Williams, Earle for Governor (Box Box 10)
  - Video-Women's Suffrage (Box Box 10)
  - Video-Women's Suffrage (Box Box 10)
  - Enlargement of a Suffrage Calendar 1912, Oversized
- Items Donated in 2003 March 1981-2002
  - Annual Report, 1990 (Box-folder 11:1)
  - Annual Report, 1991 (Box-folder 11:2)
  - Annual Report, 1992 (Box-folder 11:3)
  - Annual Report, 1993 (Box-folder 11:4)
  - Annual Report, 1994 (Box-folder 11:5)
  - Annual Report, 1995 (Box-folder 11:6)
  - Annual Report, 1996 (Box-folder 11:7)
  - Annual Report, 1997 (Box-folder 11:8)
  - Annual Report, 1998 (Box-folder 11:9)
  - Annual Report, 1999 (Box-folder 11:10)
  - Annual Report, 2000 (Box-folder 11:11)
  - Annual Report, 2001 (Box-folder 11:12)
  - Annual Report, 2002 (Box-folder 11:13)
  - Board of Directors, 1994-1999 (Box-folder 11:14)
  - Board Referendum, 1996 (Box-folder 11:15)
  - Candidate Forum with Junior League, October 15, 1995 (Box-folder 11:16)
  - Correspondence, Minutes, Agendas, Ballot Issues, Cahnnel 12 Volunteers, Project America Action, circa 1990s (Box-folder 11:17)
  - Facts For Voters, 1995 (Box-folder 11:18)
  - Guide, National Voter Registration Drive, 1992, 1995, 1996 (Box-folder 11:19)
  - Debates and Forums, circa 1990s (Box-folder 11:20)
  - Members Handbook, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 11:21)
  - Member Handbook, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 11:22)
  - Membership Directory, 1994-2002 (Box-folder 11:23)
  - Membership Lists, Yearbook, 1954-1972, 1976 (Box-folder 11:24)
  - Membership Roster, June 3, 1997- June 17, 1997 (Box-folder 11:25)
  - Metro Dinner, 1996 (Box-folder 11:26)
  - Minutes and Agendas, 1997 January 8-1997 November 5 (Box-folder 11:27)
  - Minutes and Agendas, 1998 January 7-1998 December 5 (Box-folder 11:28)
  - Minutes and Agendas, 1999 January 9-1999 May 5 (Box-folder 11:29)
  - Minutes and Agendas, 1993 June 30- 1993 November 3 (Box-folder 11:30)
  - Minutes and Agendas, 1994 January 4- 1994 December 5 (Box-folder 11:31)
  - Minutes and Agendas, 1995 January 4-1995 November 1 (Box-folder 11:32)
  - Minutes and Agendas, 1996 January 3- 1996 December 4 (Box-folder 11:33)
  - Motor Voter Registration, undated (Box-folder 11:34)
  - Roster, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 11:35)
  - U.S. Senate Candidate Forum, undated (Box-folder 11:36)
  - Virginia Foundation for Women, undated (Box-folder 11:37)
  - Voter Service Committee Meeting, Debate watch, March 12, 1996, April 27, 1994, June 17, 1996, September 14, 1998 (Box-folder 11:38)
- Materials Concerning the Project for Mental Health of Homeless 1980-1990 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1989 (Box-folder 12:1)
  - Documents and Reports, 1987 (Box-folder 12:2)
  - Documents and Reports, 1989 (Box-folder 12:3)
  - Documents and Reports, 1990 (Box-folder 12:4)
  - Mental Health Study, 1980s (Box-folder 12:5)
  - Mental Health Study, 1980s (Box-folder 12:6)
  - Miscellaneous Documents, circa 1980s-1990 (Box-folder 12:7)
  - Richmond Project for Homeless Adults with Mental Illness, 1990 (Box-folder 12:8)
  - Enlargement of a Suffrage Calendar, 1912 (Oversize Map Drawer 26)
- Donations made after 2003, 1979-1991 (Box 13)
  - ABC of County Government, undated (Box-folder 13:1)
  - Candidate Questionnare Federal Offices, 1990 (Box-folder 13:2)
  - Channel 23, Meet the Candidates, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 13:3)
  - Chesterfield Referenda, 1988 (Box-folder 13:4)
  - City Council Candidates and Questionnaire, 1986 (Box-folder 13:5)
  - Debate, 1987 (Box-folder 13:6)
  - Debate, Questions for the Candidate Meetings, 1986 (Box-folder 13:7)
  - Diekroeger, 1981 (Box-folder 13:8)
  - Education Materials, 1980s (Box-folder 13:9)
  - Election Guide-- Local Voters Guide, 1985 (Box-folder 13:10)
  - Election Results, November General Election, 1987 (Box-folder 13:11)